# Arjun Naik October 29, 1987

Arjun.RN@gmail.com • +49.17657886406 • arjun-naik (*Skype*)

https://de.linkedin.com/in/arnaik

Gret-Palucca-Str. 9, Whng 1214 • 01069 • Dresden • Germany

## Summary

A organised, meticulous, and determined software engineering with a focus on building distributed systems.

It has been 10 years since I picked up a book on C programming. Since then I have been led deeper into the world of software development. My discovery of Python was the second biggest turning point. This sparked my interest in Web applications and subsequently Distributed Systems.

After obtaining a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Engineering I spent 2 years working at a consul-

tancy. Here I built the front-end for India's largest pizza chain. After that I moved to a startup where I built web applications and got interested in Android development.

After 2 years of working at a startup I decided to continue my education in Germany. Studying at TU Dresden in the Systems Engineering chair has given me a unique opportunity to participate is several diverse research projects.

## Experience

Netbramha Studios Web Developer

Bangalore, India

Oct 2010 - May 2011

Development with a variety of PHP frameworks. Also basic JQuery apps. Developed a Django web application for location based offers.

Locus Labs

Bangalore, India

## Web and Mobile Developer

Iun 2011 - August 2012

Development of Android app and web app for location based credit card offers. Crawling and scraping of websites to collect the data and collate the information. Development of server backend for location based offer-alerts using Tornado. Android SDK for apps utilizing this service.

**DMFS** 

Dresden, Germany

## **Application Developer**

Jan 2013 - March 2014

Development of Android app for Task Management based on the CalDav protocol. Interface for in-app calendar store. Built a Django based server-based for mobile app multi-retail using OpenSSL.

**DMFS** 

Dresden, Germany

#### **Systems Developer**

*Mar* 2014 - Jul 2014

Maintence of Web Application based on custom PHP framework and bootstrap. Development of monitoring service for all the external services.

TU Dresden

Dresden, Germany

#### Wissenschaftliche Hilfskraft

Mar 2013 - Present

Development of Python-powered translator for C programs for secure(encoded) execution. Comparison of Zookeeper and Consul services.

Please consult my LinkedIn Profile for references.

#### **Education**

BM Sreenivasaiah College of Engineering, Vivesvararya Technological University Bangalore, India **Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering** 2006 - 2010

Programmeren in Java, Android applicaties, etc.

Techniche UniversitÄďt Dresden

Dresden, Germany

Master of Science, Distributed Systems Engineering

Programmeren in Java, Android applicaties, etc.

2012 - 2014

## Skills

Technical Specialities: Python Django Git Android CSS REST JSON HTML Node.js JavaScript jQuery Web Scraping Google App Engine Tornado Mercurial Concurrent Programming JNI Java Web Development Fault Tolerance Distributed Systems Database Development System Deployment Subversion Cryptography

Data Synchronization Natural Languages: English (Bilingual Proficiency), Hindi (Native), Kannada (Native), German (Limited profi-

ciency).

## Interests

Science-Fiction, photography, hardware hacking, good coffee

Consult my Github profile for a complete list of my projects.